RICHA SHAURBH

2400 4th Ave #567 Seattle WA 98121

+1 (206) 953-3929 richa.shaurabh@gmail.com

github.com/richaSha linkedin.com/in/richa-shaurabh-22ab24142

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Web/Frontend Developer with more than 4 years of professional experience and expertise in a wide array of frontend technologies, like HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, etc. demonstrated in onsite & offshore industrial projects spanning the telecom domain to home automation.

EDUCATION

SRM University, Chennai, India

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering

Graduated in 2008

2008-2012

GPA: 7.8 / 10.0

Patna Women's College

Higher Secondary School

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming skills: Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, React.js, HTML, CSS, Ruby, PostgreSQL

Testing Frameworks: Jasmine, Karma

Tools: Git, npm, Sublime Text

OS Experience: MacOS, Windows

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LG Soft India

Apr 2015 – Jul 2017

Software Developer

Bangalore, India

- Development of "Enact" which is LG's next generation Javascript framework based on React.js. It is used for developing native-quality HTML5 apps that can run on any device.
- Firefox Mobile OS development for LG Fx0 phone Developed & optimized the Camera & Gallery apps, atop the Gaia User Interface application, using Object Oriented Javascript.

Tech Mahindra

Nov 2013 – Apr 2015

Software Developer

Bangalore, India & Sydney, Australia

- Optus Mobile Network Coverage & Diagnosis application Designed & developed a frontend application that showed network tower diagnosis information on a map to customers of Optus (Australian telecom). It also let customers log complaints against specific towers and get responses from Optus Engineers.
- Technologies used: Object Oriented Javascript & the OpenLayers library.

FLORET Media

Jan 2013 - Nov 2013

Web Developer

Bangalore, India

 Responsive website development for online marketing of FLORET Media clients using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery & AngularJS.

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Epicodus Certified "Web and Mobile Development" engineer Met all the certification requirements: Javascript, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ruby and PostgreSQL.
- Sports Awarded by the State government for winning in the Throwball league for the state of Bihar, India

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Doctors Search An interface that allows users to search for Doctors in a certain area based on a medical condition, doctor's name and other similar search criteria using the BetterDoctor API.
- Mykart An eCommerce website with user interfaces to show product details, product listings and shopping carts.

2017